904–1307 Harwood St, Vancouver, BC, V6E 1S7 (604) 349 8750 – thomas.tartiere@gmail.com

Lead Software Developer and Energy Engineer



PROFILE

Entrepreneur mindset, thorough experience in fast-paced environments.

Strong analytical skills with solid understanding of the energy industry, SaaS product development and data science.

Strong interpersonal skills, as demonstrated through leading and collaborating in multidisciplinary teams.

Results driven project manager with proven success in completing projects on time.

Multilingual: Fluent in French, English & Spanish; basic Russian & German.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Developer

01/2017 to Now

Panevo, Vancouver

Managed all aspects of software development from roadmap to operation and customer support:

- Built and launched a new SaaS cloud platform to process
 & visualize energy data from large industrial corporations
- Designed a utility bill management system to detect anomalies in tens of thousands of electric, gas, water & telecom bills

R&D Project Manager

01/2012 to 12/2016

Enertime, Paris then Vancouver

Led the development & modeling of innovative clean energy technologies:

- Developed software tools for advanced modeling and optimization of industrial systems
- Coordinated multidisciplinary teams in multi-million \$ research projects
- Published 8 conference & journal articles, 1 patent

EDUCATION

Online (Coursera, Udacity...)

2015 to now

Completed 10+ courses on Machine Learning & Data science

Stanford University, USA

2009-2010

M. Sc. in Mechanical Engineering (Energy Sciences)

Ecole Centrale Paris, France

2008-2010

M. Sc in General Engineering

Preparatory classes in Sciences, France 2006-2008

Intensive preparation for top Engineering Schools

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Programming: Python, C\C++, Javascript
- Full-stack web development
 - Back-End (Django/Flask, REST API, Redis, RabbitMQ)
 - Front-End (Vue.JS, JS tools)
 - DevOps (Microsoft Azure)
- Data science and machine learning (Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn)
- Deep Learning (Tensor Flow, Keras)
- Energy system design and optimization
- Business development and B2B sales
- Project Management Professional (PMP)
- Professional Engineer (P. Eng.)
- Professional written and oral communication

ACCOMPLISHMENTS / AWARDS

- Award for the Best Student Project at Ecole Centrale Paris (2010)
- Rotary Foundation Ambassadorial Scholarship (2010)
- Rowing Club President, Ecole Centrale Paris (2009-2010): involved in national and international university events.
- French National Programming Competition : Finalist (2005)